An epic story of love.
Anna Karenina is a drama, romance, history film directed by Joe Wright.
In Imperial Russia, Anna, wife of the officer Karenin,
goes to Moscow to visit her brother.
On the way, she meets charming cavalry officer Vronsky,
to whom she's immediately attracted.
Petersburg’s high society, a relationship like this
could destroy a woman’s reputation.
Anna Karenina, played by Keira Knightley.
Karenin, played by Jude Law.
Vronsky, played by Aaron Taylor-Johnson.
Oblonsky, played by Matthew Macfadyen.
Matvey, played by Eric MacLennan.
Dolly, played by Kelly Macdonald.
Anna Karenina is a 2012 historical romantic drama film directed by Joe Wright.
Adapted by Tom Stoppard from Leo Tolstoy's 1878 novel, the film depicts the tragedy of Russian aristocrat and socialite Anna
Karenina, wife of senior statesman Alexei Karenin, and her affair with the affluent cavalry officer Count Vronsky.
Keira Knightley stars as the titular character; this is her third collaboration with
director Joe Wright following Pride & Prejudice (2005) and Atonement (2007).
Jude Law and Aaron Taylor-Johnson appear as Karenin and Vronsky, respectively.
Matthew Macfadyen, Kelly Macdonald, Domhnall Gleeson, and
Alicia Vikander appear in key supporting roles.
Produced by Working Title Films in association with StudioCanal, the
film premiered at the 2012 Toronto Film Festival.
It was released on 7 September 2012 in the United Kingdom
and on 16 November 2012 in the United States.
Anna Karenina earned a worldwide gross of approximately $69
million, mostly from its international run.
The film received mostly positive reviews: critics praised the cast, but commented on and criticized the heavily stylized adaptation, and were
less enthusiastic with Wright's preference for style over substance and his idea of setting most of the action on a theatre stage.
It earned four nominations at the 85th Academy Awards and six nominations at the 66th British Academy Film
Awards, winning Jacqueline Durran both the Academy Award and the BAFTA Award for Best Costume Design.
In addition, Anna Karenina garnered six nominations at the 17th Satellite Awards,
including Best Actress for Knightley and Best Adapted Screenplay for Stoppard.
The film explores themes of adultery, based on novel or book,
horse race, st. petersburg, russia, death.
The tone is emotional.